Can Bogoclu, PhD

♥ Düsseldorf, Germany | ★ canbooo.github.io

□ can.bogoclu@gmail.com | □ canbooo | R⁶ Can-Bogoclu | □ can-bogoclu

personal summary

Lang.: Turkish, English, German

7+ years of experience in machine learning • small data and active learning expertise • experience with big data and **distributed training** • highly skilled at visualization • endless love for learning and teaching • secret crush on reinforcement learning

Nation.: Turkish

experience

Legal: EU Blue Card for Germany

Applied Scientist

Zalando SE since July 2022

machine learning

- - Significant accuracy and precision improvement already in the second month
 - Distributed training on AWS using workflows and step functions
 - Agile team and methodology

deep learning

Probabilistic and

Reinforcement Associate Lecturer

learning

Niederrhein University of Applied Sciences

Oct. 2019-Sep. 2022

Bayesian optimization Math for first year engineering students (1 semester)

Probabilistic fulfillment and delivery time estimation

• Computer science for engineering students (2 semesters)

Uncertainty

• Introduction to Machine Learning for computer science students (1 semester)

quantification

Probabilistic machine learning for engineering students (1 semester)

Hypothesis testing

Mentored a PhD student

development

Python | 8+ yrs bash | 6+ yrs git | 4+ yrs Javascript | 1+ yrs

(Senior) Software Developer and Data Scientist

Probaligence GmbH

Sep. 2018-June 2022

- STOCHOS, an automated machine learning module for engineers. Flavors: python module, web-based GUI, ANSYS optiSlang add-in.
- KILU, AI research for aviation, partner: German Aerospace Center (DLR). Topics: material modelling, geometric mesh analysis

• RLTC, RL for trajectory control, partner: ZF Friedrichshafen AG. Task: Uncertainty aware reinforcement learning for autonomous vehicles

• iFoot, intelligent bandage for diabetic foot. Tasks: Smart watch app, Web servers for data pipeline and patient tracking

tools

tensorflow, torch jax, scikit-learn xaboost

pandas, dask matplotlib, dash seaborn, plotly

django, selenium

pytest, nose unittest

databases

ray, dvc

Research Assistant

Niederrhein University of Applied Science

Jan. 2015-Oct. 2019

- MeZuMe, electric motor uncertainty optimization, partner: Bosch GmbH
- Learning from vector and field data for structural anomaly detection
- High-performance computing cluster administration

AWS Lambda/Step docker

education

PhD Mechanical Engineering, Ruhr-Universität Bochum 2015-2022 Thesis: Machine learning accelerated design uncertainty optimization

Diplom (B.Sc. + M.Sc.) Mechanical Engineering, RWTH Aachen SQLite | 2+ yrs Thesis: Modelling and experimental validation of hydraulic pump housings postgresql | 1+ yrs